// import { useState } from 'react'
import { useState } from 'react';
import './App.css'
import Flashcard from './components/Flashcard'; // Adjust the path if necessary


function App() {
  // variable to keep track of the current index of the flashcard
  const [currentIndex, setCurrentIndex] = useState(0);
  // variable to keep track of the current state of the flashcard
  const [flipped, setFlipped] = useState(false);
  // set an array of flashcards with questions and answers
  const flashcard_list = [
    {question: "What is bagel in Spanish?", answer: "Bagel!"},
    {question: "What is cream cheese in Spanish?", answer: "Queso Crema!"},
    {question: "What is coffee in Spanish?", answer: "Cafe!"},
    {question: "What is tea in Spanish?", answer: "Te!"},
    {question: "What is Spanish in Spanish?", answer: "Espanol!"},
    {question: "What is English in Spanish?", answer: "Ingles!"},
    {question: "What is Bread in Spanish?", answer: "Pan!"},
    {question: "What is Butter in Spanish?", answer: "Mantequilla!"},
    {question: "What is Cat in Spanish?", answer: "Gato!"},
    {question: "What is the inverse of the parobola in Spanish?", answer: "Idk!"},
    {question: "What is Dog in Spanish?", answer: "Perro!"},
    {question: "What is Fish in Spanish?", answer: "Pescado!"},
    {question: "What is Horse in Spanish?", answer: "Caballo!"},
    {question: "What is Cow in Spanish?", answer: "Vaca!"},
    {question: "What is Pig in Spanish?", answer: "Puerco!"},
    {question: "What is Chicken in Spanish", answer: "Pollo!"},
    {question: "What is Duck in Spanish?", answer: "Pato!"},
    {question: "What is Turkey in Spanish?", answer: "Pavo!"},
    {question: "What is Sheep in Spanish?", answer: "Oveja!"},
    {question: "What is Goat in Spanish?", answer: "Chiva!"},
  ]

  const handlePrevCard = () => {
    setFlipped(false);
    setCurrentIndex((prevIndex) => (prevIndex - 1 + flashcard_list.length) % flashcard_list.length);
  }

  // handles the next card in our flashcards array
  const handleNextCard = () => {
    setFlipped(false);
    setCurrentIndex((prevIndex) => (prevIndex + 1) % flashcard_list.length);
  };

  const handleFlipCard = () => {
    setFlipped(!flipped);
  };


  const handleRandomCard = () => {
    setFlipped(false);
    let randomIndex;
    do {
      randomIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * flashcard_list.length);
    } while (randomIndex === currentIndex);
    setCurrentIndex(randomIndex);
  };

  return (
    <>
      <div className='app'>
        <h1 className='header'>SPANISH FLASHCARDS!!</h1>
        <h3>Total Cards: {flashcard_list.length}</h3>
        <div className='flashcard-inner'>
          <Flashcard
            flipped={flipped}
            onFlip={handleFlipCard}
            question={flashcard_list[currentIndex].question}
            answer={flashcard_list[currentIndex].answer}
          />
      </div>
        <div>
          
        </div>
        <div className='button-layout'>
          <button className='button' onClick={handlePrevCard}>‚¨ÖÔ∏è Previous </button>
          <button className='button' onClick={handleNextCard}>‚û°Ô∏è Next</button>
          <button className='button' onClick={handleRandomCard}>üîÄ Shuffle Next Card</button>
        </div>
      </div>
    </>
  )
}

export default App
